tool_text Ver 0.0.3.2
--

■ Introduction
A plug-in that extends the text processing capabilities of CLCL.

■ Installation
This tool works with CLCL version 2.0.0 or higher.

Place tool_text.dll in the appropriate directory, open the CLCL options screen and display the Tools tab. You can then select a tool to add by clicking the Add button and specifying tool_text.dll.
You can register multiple tools at once by opening the Tools tab in Options and dragging tool_text.dll there.

When updating, close CLCL and overwrite tool_text.dll.
When uninstalling, remove the tool from CLCL and then delete tool_text.dll.

If you don't see tool_text.dll during installation, you may have a setting that hides the DLL. Please set "Show hidden files and folders" in File Explorer folder options.

■ Functions
・Date conversion
    Convert any string to the current date and time.

    When "When sending data to clipboard" is enabled in the CLCL tool settings, any character string is automatically converted to a date and time when the text data in the registered element is sent to the clipboard.
    The string to be converted
      %d - date
      %t - time
    The date and time format can be set by clicking the "Properties" button in the CLCL tool settings.

・Convert to lowercase
・Upper case
    Converts alphabetic characters to upper and lower case.

Quote
・Unquote marks
    Appends the specified string to the beginning of the string.

    Quotes can be set on the settings screen every time you run the tool, but if you specify a command line for the quote tool, the characters specified on the command line will be used as quotes. You can register multiple quoting tools and use them properly by specifying quotes on the command line.

·Text formatting
    Wraps text by the specified number of bytes.

    The number of bytes to wrap can be set in the settings screen each time you run the tool, but if you specify a command line for the text formatting tool, it will wrap by the number specified on the command line.

・Insert text
    Combines text with the specified string.

    The characters to be pasted can be set on the settings screen each time the tool is launched, but if you specify a command line for the text pasting tool, it will be pasted with the character string specified on the command line.
    How to specify
      <TAG>,</TAG>,0
    Separate start and end with ",". 0 - if escape characters will not be used, 1 - if they will (\t, \r, \n)
    If you use "," in a string, escape it with \, like "\,".

    You can register multiple text insertion tools and specify a character string to be inserted on the command line.

・Remove line breaks
    Removes newlines (CR, LF) from text.

    You can customize the removal of leading spaces by clicking the "Properties" button on the CLCL tool's setup screen.
    The initial value is to remove leading spaces.
    You can set the command line to 1 - remove leading spaces, 0 - do not remove, ? - ask when calling.

・Text concatenation
    Combine multiple text data and send it to the clipboard.

    Concatenate displays the history and registered items in the list (right pane) in the CLCL viewer, selects multiple items, and invokes the tool to concatenate the selected items and send them to the clipboard.
    Clicking the properties button in the CLCL tool settings allows you to set a line break to be inserted between the combined texts.
    It is also possible to set the gap between the combined texts as a single space. You can choose to merge text in reverse order.
    Can you set the command line ? - ask when calling.

・Text editing
    You can edit text on a simple edit screen.

    Set the call from the operation menu, right-click the history menu in CLCL, display the tool list, and select the text editing tool to display the editing screen. After editing, click the [OK] button to change the contents.
    You can set the window font using a setting in the tool_text.ini file
 
--
The author is not responsible for any damage caused by this program.
It is highly recommended that you back up your important files.

Please send bug reports, requests and questions to nakka@nakka.com.

Copyright (C) 1996-2022 by Ohno Tomoaki. All rights reserved.
  http://www.nakka.com/

Project created in "Microsoft Visual Studio Community 2022"
2022/12/01
