tool_find Ver 0.0.2.2
--

■ Introduction
A plug-in that looks for strings in CLCL elements.

■ Installation
This tool works with CLCL version 2.0.0 or higher.

Place tool_find.dll in the appropriate directory, open the CLCL options screen and display the Tools tab. You can then select a tool to add by clicking the add button and pointing to tool_find.dll.
You can register multiple tools at once by opening the Tools tab in Options and dragging tool_find.dll there.

If you want to upgrade, exit CLCL and overwrite tool_find.dll.
When uninstalling, remove the tool from CLCL and then delete tool_find.dll.

If you don't see tool_find.dll during installation, you may have a setting that hides the DLL. Please set "Show hidden files and folders" in File Explorer folder options.

■ Functions
·Search
    Enter a search string to find items containing that string. You can select the search bar that you opened earlier.
    The search target is only the TEXT format.
    You can set the search to be case sensitive. You can set the search box to re-show if you prefer.    

·Find next
    Search for the next element using the string specified in the search.
    If no search string is set, the search string input screen will be displayed.

Assigning a hotkey to a tool will bring up the viewer and start searching

--
The author is not responsible for any damage caused by this program.
It is highly recommended that you back up your important files.

Please send bug reports, requests and questions to nakka@nakka.com

Copyright (C) 1996-2023 by Ohno Tomoaki. All rights reserved.
	http://www.nakka.com/

Project created in "Microsoft Visual Studio Community 2022"
2023/02/23
