fmt_metafile Ver 0.0.2
--

■ Introduction
A format plug-in that handles Windows Metafiles and Enhanced Metafiles in CLCL.


■ Installation
This tool works with CLCL Ver 2.0.0 or later.

Place fmt_metafile.dll in an appropriate directory, open the CLCL option screen, and display the "Format" tab. Then you can select the clipboard format to add by pressing the add button and specifying fmt_metafile.dll.
You can register multiple clipboard formats at once by opening the "Format" tab in the options and dragging and dropping fmt_metafile.dll there.

If you want to upgrade, close CLCL and overwrite fmt_metafile.dll.
When uninstalling, remove the format from CLCL and then delete fmt_metafile.dll.

If you can't find fmt_metafile.dll when you install it, you may have a setting that hides the DLL. Please set "Show hidden files and folders" in folder options of explorer.

■ Functions
Windows metafile (METAFILE PICTURE) and enhanced metafile (ENHANCED METAFILE) can be displayed in the viewer, and a reduced image is displayed in the menu specified by the action.

--
The author is not responsible for any damage caused by this program.
It is strongly recommended to back up important files.

Please send bugs, requests and questions to nakka@nakka.com.

Copyright (C) 1996-2015 by Ohno Tomoaki. All rights reserved.
    http://www.nakka.com/

2015/09/05
