fmt_rtf Ver 0.0.2
--

■ Introduction
Format plug-in that handles rich text in CLCL.

■ Installation
This tool works with CLCL Ver 2.0.0 or later.

Place fmt_rtf.dll in an appropriate directory, open the option screen of CLCL, and display the "Format" tab. Then you can select the clipboard format to add by pressing the add button and specifying fmt_rtf.dll.
You can register multiple clipboard formats at once by opening the "Format" tab in the options and dragging and dropping fmt_rtf.dll there.

If you want to upgrade, close CLCL and overwrite fmt_rtf.dll.
When uninstalling, remove the format from CLCL and then delete fmt_rtf.dll.

If you can't find fmt_rtf.dll when you install it, you may have a setting that hides the DLL. Please set "Show hidden files and folders" in folder options of explorer.

■ Functions
You can view and edit rich text format in the viewer.

--
The author is not responsible for any damage caused by this program.
It is strongly recommended to back up important files.

Please send bugs, requests and questions to her at nakka@nakka.com.

Copyright (C) 1996-2015 by Ohno Tomoaki. All rights reserved.
    http://www.nakka.com/

2015/09/05
