tool_bitmap Ver 0.0.2
--

■ Introduction
A plug-in tool that extends CLCL's bitmap processing.

■ Installation
This tool works with CLCL Ver 2.0.0 or later.

Place tool_bitmap.dll in an appropriate directory, open the option screen of CLCL, and display the "Tools" tab. Then, you can select the tool to add by pressing the Add button and specifying tool_bitmap.dll.
You can register multiple tools at once by opening the "Tools" tab in Options and dragging and dropping tool_bitmap.dll there.

If you want to upgrade, exit CLCL and overwrite tool_bitmap.dll.
When uninstalling, remove the tool from CLCL and then remove tool_bitmap.dll.

If you don't see tool_bitmap.dll when you install it, you may have a setting that hides the DLL. Please set "Show hidden files and folders" in folder options of explorer.

■ Functions
・Bitmap editing
     Save the bitmap to a file and pass it to an external application to make it editable.
     This tool is used by invoking it from the Viewer Tools menu.
    
     The external application to be started can be set by pressing the property button in CLCL's tool settings. The initial value is Paint that comes with Windows.

--
The author is not responsible for any damage caused by this program.
It is strongly recommended to back up important files.

Please send bugs, requests and questions to her at nakka@nakka.com.

Copyright (C) 1996-2015 by Ohno Tomoaki. All rights reserved.
    http://www.nakka.com/

2015/09/05
