tool_history Ver 0.0.2.1
--

■ Introduction
A plug-in that extends the CLCL history feature.

■ Installation
This tool works with CLCL version 2.0.0 or higher.

Place tool_history.dll in the appropriate directory, open the CLCL options screen and display the Tools tab. You can then select a tool to add by clicking the Add button and specifying tool_history.dll.
You can register multiple tools at once by opening the Tools tab in Options and dragging tool_history.dll there.

If you want to upgrade, close CLCL and overwrite tool_history.dll.
When uninstalling, remove the tool from CLCL and then delete tool_history.dll.

If you don't see tool_history.dll during installation, you may have a setting that hides the DLL. Please set "Show hidden files and folders" in File Explorer folder options.

■ Functions
・Hierarchical history management
    History entries that exceed the specified number are automatically grouped into a folder.

    It only works when the "When adding data to history" option is enabled in the CLCL tool settings.
    When you click the "Properties" button in the CLCL tool settings, you can set "History Display Count", "Folder Count", "Items in Folder Count", and "Folder Name Format".

    The total number of items in the history when this tool is enabled is the number of items displayed in the history + the number of folders * the number of items in the folder.

    The CLCL option "Number of records to keep in history" has no value. Please set the "number of records to keep" to the number of displayed history + the number of folders + 1 or more.

    Automatically create folders when adding items to history. Since the folder name is fixed, even if you change it, the folder name will be restored each time an item is added to the history.

--
The author is not responsible for any damage caused by this program.
It is highly recommended that you back up your important files.

Please send bug reports, requests and questions to nakka@nakka.com

Copyright (C) 1996-2022 by Ohno Tomoaki. All rights reserved.
	http://www.nakka.com/

Project created in "Microsoft Visual Studio Community 2022"
2022/12/01
