tool_utl Ver 0.0.3.1
--

■ Introduction
This is a plug-in that extends the functionality of CLCL.

■ Installation
This tool works with CLCL version 2.0.0 or higher.

Place tool_utl.dll in the appropriate directory, open the CLCL options screen and display the Tools tab. You can then select a tool to add by clicking the Add button and specifying tool_utl.dll.
You can register multiple tools at once by opening the Tools tab in Options and dragging tool_utl.dll there.

If you want to upgrade, close CLCL and overwrite tool_utl.dll.
When uninstalling, remove the tool from CLCL and then delete tool_utl.dll.

If you don't see tool_utl.dll during installation, you may have a setting that hides the DLL. Please set "Show hidden files and folders" in File Explorer folder options.

■ Functions
Clean history
    Delete all history items.

・Clear clipboard
    Clear the contents of the clipboard.

·Sound
    Play a sound when an item is added to a story.

    When the "When adding data to history" option is enabled in the CLCL tool settings, a sound will sound when data is added to the history.
    You can select the sound to play by clicking the property button in the CLCL instrument settings.

・Top All Windows
・Undo on top of all windows
    Set or disable the viewer to the front.

    When the "View Menu" is enabled in the CLCL tool settings, set or disable the viewer from the tools menu in the CLCL viewer.
    Set the viewer to front when opening the CLCL viewer when "When opening the viewer" is enabled in the CLCL Tool Preferences.

・Save multiple items
    Save multiple items to a file named.

    View the history and registered items in the list (right pane) in the CLCL Viewer, select multiple items, and select this tool.
    When you run the tool, select the output destination and set the information to save.
    The save information sets the file format and name. The format combo box contains all the formats of the items to save, so select the format to save.
    To choose.
    Filenames can be numbered with %d.

--
The author is not responsible for any damage caused by this program.
It is highly recommended that you back up your important files.

Please send bug reports, requests and questions to nakka@nakka.com

Copyright (C) 1996-2022 by Ohno Tomoaki. All rights reserved.
	http://www.nakka.com/

Project created in "Microsoft Visual Studio Community 2022"
2022/12/01
